<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<info:toolkitInfoModel xmlns:common="http://www.ibm.com/xmlns/prod/streams/spl/common" xmlns:info="http://www.ibm.com/xmlns/prod/streams/spl/toolkitInfo">
  <info:identity>
    <info:name>com.ibm.streamsx.jdbc</info:name>
    <info:description>The JDBCRun operator runs a user-defined SQL statement that is based on an input tuple. 
    
  The statement is run once for each input tuple received. Result sets that are produced by the statement are emitted as output stream tuples. 
    
  The **JDBCRun** operator is commonly used to update, merge, and delete database management system (DBMS) records. 
  
  This operator is also used to retrieve records, create and drop tables, and to call stored procedures. 

  Behavior in a consistent region:
  
  The **JDBCRun** operator can be used in a consistent region. 
  
  It cannot be the start operator of a consistent region. In a consistent region, the configured value of the transactionSize is ignored. Instead, database commits are performed (when supported by the DBMS) on consistent region checkpoints, and database rollbacks are performed on consistent region resets.
  
  On **drain**: If there are any pending statements, they are run. If the statement generates a result set and the operator has an output port, tuples are generated from the results and submitted to the output port. If the operator has an error output port and the statement generates any errors, tuples are generated from the errors and submitted to the error output port.
  
  On **checkpoint**: A database commit is performed.
  
  On **reset**: Any pending statements are discarded. A rollback is performed.

  The JDBCRun operator support **optional type** feature.

  It supports also **phoenix jdbc** to connect to the HBASE database.
  
  The **JDBCRun** operator has been improved in version 1.4.0 with a new parameter **checkConnection**. This optional parameter specifies whether a **checkConnection** thread should be start. It checks periodically the status of JDBC connection. The JDBCRun sends in case of any failure a SqlCode and a message to SPL application.
  
  ++ What is new in version 1.4.3

  * The JDBCRun operators provides a new parameter **credentials**. 
    This optional parameter specifies a JSON string that contains the JDBC credentials.
    The JDBC credentials string must contain valid JSON format and a set of name/value pairs for
    **username**, **password** and **jdbcurl**. 

  * support **Streams application configuration** 
 
 ++ What is new in version 1.4.4
 
 * Insert BLOB bug fixed #82
  
++ What is new in version 1.5.0
 
 * Add **jdbcUrl** to the jdbc properties.
 * Support both **jdbcUrl** and **jdbcurl** in credentials and in properties file.

</info:description>
    <info:version>1.5.0</info:version>
    <info:requiredProductVersion>4.2.0.0</info:requiredProductVersion>
  </info:identity>
  <info:dependencies/>
</info:toolkitInfoModel>
